Guide to the Nate Larson Photographs, 2015 RL.11419
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Nate Larson photographs
2015
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Larson, Nate
RL.11419
1 Linear Feet 2 boxes; 63 items; 13 x 19 inches
Collection comprises a set of 48 color photographs, 13 reproductions of historic postcards, and several introductory panels, from a project by photographer and artist Nate Larson entitled "Map of All the Railroads," inspired by H.V. Poor's "Map of All the Railroads in the United States in Operation and Progress" (1854). The 13x19 inch digital color photographs, taken in 2015, explore social and economic aspects of thirteen railroad-centered cities and towns identified in Poor's publication, and their progress and potential future. Images feature cityscapes, railroad tracks, buildings and businesses, abandoned sites, monuments, several portraits of people, and other subjects. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Biographical / Historical
Nate Larson is a contemporary artist working with photographic media, artist books and digital video. His projects have been widely shown across the United States and internationally as well as featured in numerous publications and media outlets.
Larson holds a full-time faculty appointment in the photography department at Maryland Institute College of Art (MICA) in Baltimore. During his 2015 sabbatical, he was the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Visiting Artist Fellow at Duke University and a Rubys Artist Project Grant Recipient from the Greater Baltimore Cultural Alliance.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Nate Larson photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Photographs are printed on Canson Infinity Baryta Photographique 310 gsm using an Epson 7900 and Epson Ultrachrome HDR ink. Introductory pages and postcard images are printed on Moab Kayenta Photo Matte 205 gsm using an Epson 7900 and Epson Ultrachrome HDR ink.
Scope and Contents
Collection comprises set of 48 color photographs, 13 reproductions of historic postcards, and several introductory panels, part of a project by photographer and artist Nate Larson entitled "Map of All the Railroads," inspired by H.V. Poor's "Map of all the Railroads in the United States in Operation and Progress" (1854). The 13x19 inch digital color photographs, taken in 2015, explore social and economic aspects of thirteen railroad-centered North Carolina cities and towns identified in Poor's book, and their progress and potential future.
The cities are: Charlotte, Concord, Gaston, Goldsboro, Greensboro, Halifax, Hillsborough, Raleigh, Salisbury, Warrenton, Wayne, Whiteville, and Wilmington. Images include views of businesses, cemeteries, railroad tracks and crossings, monuments, construction sites, abandoned buildings, and several portraits of people.
The artist's statement reads: "In November 2105, I visited twelve of these cities and the site of one former city to survey their progress and contemplate their future. These photographs are observations of the man-altered American landscape and seek to understand of the human experience within it. The images function as a meditation on the passage of time, shifting dynamics of progress and development, and the peculiarities of historic events that shape the present."
Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Arrangement
Arranged in plate number order as assigned by artist.
Cities and towns -- North Carolina; Documentary Photography -- North Carolina; Postcards -- North Carolina; Railroads -- Economic aspects -- Southern States; Railroads -- North Carolina -- History; Railroads -- Social aspects -- Southern States; North Carolina -- History; North Carolina -- Pictorial works; Color photographs; Inkjet prints; Digital prints; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University); Larson, Nate
- Map of all the Railroads, 2015; 1
  - Statement and list of plates with graphic from H.V. Poor's Map of all the Railroads in the United States in Operation and Progress (1854), 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0001)
  - Map of North Carolina, from H.V. Poor's Map of all the Railroads in the United States in Operation and Progress (1854), 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0002)
  - Scanned postcards of Charlotte, from the Postcard Collection of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0003)
  - Sports Field, Charlotte, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0004)
  - Dairy Queen, Charlotte, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0005)
  - Paper Doll Lounge, Charlotte, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0006)
  - Scanned postcards of Concord, from the Postcard Collection of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0007)
  - In Memory, Concord, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0008)
  - Honorio, Concord, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0009)
  - Sports Field and Parking Lot, Concord, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0010)
  - Real Estate Offices, Concord, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0011)
  - Or Go to Hell, Concord, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0012)
  - Google Map of Gaston, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0013)
  - Paper Plant, Gaston, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0014)
  - Hardee's, Gaston, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0015)
  - Abandoned School, Gaston, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0016)
  - Auto Dealership, Gaston, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0017)
  - Scanned postcards of Goldsboro, from the Postcard Collection of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0018)
  - Cory, Goldsboro, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0019)
  - Railroad Tracks, Goldsboro, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0020)
  - Cash Discount, Goldsboro, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0021)
  - Plate Glass, Goldsboro, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0022)
  - Mural, Goldsboro, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0023)
  - Scanned postcard of Greensboro, from the Postcard Collection of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0024)
  - Intersection, Greensboro, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0025)
  - Home, Greensboro, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0026)
  - Computer & Electronic Services, Greensboro, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0027)
  - Greensboro Massacre Site, Greensboro, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0028)
  - Railroad Tracks, Greensboro, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0029)
  - Scanned postcard of Halifax, from the Postcard Collection of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0030)
  - Cotton Field, Halifax, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0031)
  - Amphitheater, Halifax, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0032)
  - Service Center, Halifax, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0033)
  - Overturned Truck, Halifax, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 1, Image RL11419-P-0034)
  - Scanned postcard of Hillsboro, from the Postcard Collection of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0035)
  - Widowmaker, Hillsborough, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0036)
  - Southern Pride, Hillsborough, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0037)
  - Business Center, Hillsborough, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0038)
  - Scanned postcards of Raleigh, from the Postcard Collection of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0039)
  - Confederate Monument, Raleigh, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0040)
  - Jesus is Coming, Raleigh, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0041)
  - Drainage Wall, Raleigh, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0042)
  - Construction Site, Raleigh, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0043)
  - Scanned postcards of Salisbury, from the Postcard Collection of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0044)
  - Cemetery, Salisbury, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0045)
  - Frost Bites, Salisbury, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0046)
  - Sell to Sell Again, Salisbury, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0047)
  - Scanned postcard of Warrenton, from the Postcard Collection of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0048)
  - Solar Farm, Warrenton, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0049)
  - Collapsed House, Warrenton, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0050)
  - Web clipping of Waynesboro history, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0051)
  - Sewer Infrastructure, Waynesboro, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0052)
  - Emma, Waynesboro, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0053)
  - Jungle Gym, Waynesboro, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0054)
  - Scanned postcard of Whiteville, from the Postcard Collection of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0055)
  - Whiteville Meat Market, Whiteville, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0056)
  - Southern Pawn & Guns, Whiteville, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0057)
  - Auto Parts, Whiteville, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0058)
  - Walking Man's Friend, Whiteville, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0059)
  - Scanned postcard of Wilmington, from the Postcard Collection of the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0060)
  - Port Entrance, Wilmington, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0061)
  - Iron Man & Step Brothers, Wilmington, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0062)
  - Railroad Tracks, Wilmington, North Carolina, 2015 (Box 2, Image RL11419-P-0063)